Guide to the Llewelyn Davies Family Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Photographs, 1870-1937; Series II; 1.25; (3 boxes)
  - PEOPLE
    - Others
      - Millar, Trixie du Maurier, 1890 (Box 7, Folder 173)
        Studio portrait by H. L. Mendelssohn
      - Senhouse, Roger, 1920 (Box 7, Folder 174)
      - Unidentified, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 175)
    - Groups
      - J.M. Barrie with others, 1870-1919 (Box 7, Folder 176)
        Includes photographs of George Meredith, Lady Cynthia Asquith, Margaret Ogilvy Barrie, Maurice Hewlett, and others
      - Unidentified, 1920, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 177)
  - PLACES
    - Adelphi studio, London, 1930 (Box 7, Folder 178)
    - Black Lake cottage, 1901 (Box 7, Folder 179)
    - Du Maurier home, Hampstead, 1892 (Box 7, Folder 180)
    - Egertown house, Berkhamsted, 1904-07 (Box 7, Folder 181)
    - Kirby Lonsdale vicarage, 1900 (Box 7, Folder 182)
    - Postbridge and River Dart, Devon, 1909 (Box 7, Folder 183)
    - Unidentified, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 184)
  - OTHER SUBJECTS
    - Barrie family tombstone, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 185)
    - Book illustration with caption, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 186)
    - Horses in field, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 187)
    - J.M. Barrie's funeral, 1937 (Box 7, Folder 188)
    - Printed advertisement quoting J. M. Barrie, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 189)
    - St. Bernard dog ("Porthos"), 1899 (Box 7, Folder 190)
    - Scene from play, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 191)
- Other Material, 1871-1960; Series III; 0.42; (1 box)
  Series III, Other Material, is organized into four subseries: Drawings, Printed Ephemera, Writings and Notes, and Other.
  - DRAWINGS
    - Du Maurier, Guy, [1871-88] (Box 8, Folder 192)
      Includes drawings of Arthur and Sylvia Llewelyn Davies
    - Llewelyn Davies, Sylvia, [ca. 1907] (Box 8, Folder 193)
      Includes drawing by Nicholas Llewelyn Davies
    - Unidentified, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 194)
  - PRINTED EPHEMERA
    - Application of Arthur Llewelyn Davies for an Assistant Readership under the Council of Legal Education, 1891 Oct (Box 8, Folder 195)
    - Clippings, 1907-60, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 196)
    - Eton College Chronicle, 1916 Feb 17 (Box 8, Folder 197)
    - Eton cricket match results, 1912, 1922 (Box 8, Folder 198)
    - Invitations, 1932-51 (Box 8, Folder 199)
    - Programs and publicity, 1904-37, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 200)
    - Schedules, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 201)
  - WRITINGS AND NOTES
    - Barrie, J. M. (James Matthew)
      - "Anon," draft fragment for "Act 1, Scene 1," holograph, 1903 Nov 23 (Box 8, Folder 202)
      - "Pirate Ship," draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 203)
      - ["To conclude with still another version..."], draft, typescript carbon, [1914] (Box 8, Folder 204)
      - Untitled fragments, holograph, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 205)
        Photographs of drafts
    - Llewelyn Davies, Arthur
      - Untitled notes, 1906-07, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 206)
    - Llewelyn Davies, Michael
      - "Eilean Chona," sonnets, photocopy of draft, holograph, corrected, and printed version, Eton College Chronicle, 1920, 1922 (Box 8, Folder 207)
      - "Reduction of Nico," report, typescript, corrected, photocopy, 1920 Apr 18 (Box 8, Folder 208)
    - [Llewelyn Davies, Nicholas?]
      - "The Dynamite King, Chapter II, The Deadman's Rock," typescript copy, addressed to J. M. Barrie, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 209)
      - Untitled drafts, holograph, 1945, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 210)
    - Unidentified (Box 8, Folder 211)
      Includes draft, holograph, of "Ancient Ballad"
  - OTHER
    - Agreement between J. M. Barrie and John Llewelyn Davies, 1903 Dec 6 (Box 8, Folder 212)
    - Certified Copy of an Entry of Birth for George Llewelyn Davies, 1945 Feb 19
    - Certified Copy of an Entry of Marriage between Peter Llewelyn Davies and Margaret Leslie Hore-Ruthven, 1932, 1939
    - "International Press Cuttings Unlimited", n.d. (Box 8, Folder 213)
      [Transcriptions of clippings?]
    - Locks of Michael Llewelyn Davies' hair, [ca. 1902] (Box 8, Folder 214)
    - Lock of Nicholas Llewelyn Davies' hair and envelope (Box 8, Folder 215)
    - My Confession Book, 1914, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 216)
      Completed in manuscript by J.M. Barrie, George, Jack, and Michael Llewelyn Davies, and others
    - Photocopy of "Plan of Ground Floor," N. 23, Camden Hills Square, Kensington, 1907 Jul 18 (Box 8, Folder 217)
    - Querist's Album, [ca. 1877-1911] (Box 8, Folder 218)
      Completed in manuscript by J.M. Barrie, George, Michael, and Nicolas Llewelyn Davies, and others. With inscription: "To James M. Barrie on his birthday, M.B."
    - Receipt from War Office, [1923?] Jan 2 (Box 8, Folder 219)
    - "Record of Breaks" relating to "Billiards", 1912 Jan 13 (Box 8, Folder 220)
    - "Souvenir from Killiecrankie", 1913 Sep (Box 8, Folder 221)
    - St. Peter's School, Seaford, report for T. L. Davies, 1934 Apr (Box 8, Folder 222)
    - Sylvia Llewelyn Davies' first will, [1907 May?] (Box 8, Folder 223)
      Includes envelope with notes by J. M. Barrie
    - Sylvia Llewelyn Davies' second will, 1910 Aug (Box 8, Folder 224)
      Inscribed by J. M. Barrie
    - Sylvia Llewelyn Davies' second will transcribed by J. M. Barrie, 1911 Mar 24 (Box 8, Folder 225)
- Oversize, 1914-1945; 3.57; (3 boxes)
  - Empty photograph album with captions (In Series II), n.d. (Box 9, Folder 226)
  - Empty photograph album with signature (In Series II), n.d. (Box 9a, Folder 226a)
  - Clippings (In Series III), 1914, 1926 (Box 10, Folder 227)
  - Certified Copy of an Entry of Birth for George Llewelyn Davies (In Series III), 1945 Feb 19 (Box 10, Folder 228)
  - Certified Copy of an Entry of Marriage between Peter Llewelyn Davies and Margaret Leslie Hore Ruthven (In Series III), 1932, 1939 (Box 10, Folder 229)
- Restricted Fragile Papers
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  - Box 1, folder 4 (Box 11, Folder 230)
  - Box 1, folder 23 (Box 11, Folder 231)
  - Box 2, folder 44 (Box 11, Folder 232)
  - Box 2, folder 80 (Box 11, Folder 233)
  - Box 8, folder 196 (Box 11, Folder 234)